<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I am Marlis! 👋</title>
    <link>https://marlisschneider.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hi, I am Marlis! 👋</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marlisschneider.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://marlisschneider.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marlisschneider.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About   I am a third year PhD candidate at the department of economics at NHH Norwegian School of Economics and affiliated with FAIR-Centre for Experimental Research on Fairness, Inequality and Rationality. I am a behavioral economist who uses field experiments, lab experiments, and theory to investigate research questions in the areas of education, childhood development and social preferences. In my research, I examine social influences on individual behavior and beliefs as well as their potential consequences for societal outcomes such as intergenerational inequality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the Dots</title>
      <link>https://marlisschneider.github.io/dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marlisschneider.github.io/dots/</guid>
      <description>Soon to come.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://marlisschneider.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marlisschneider.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Get in touch I love getting email. I’ve met some of my best friends this way, and a thoughtful message from a new person is always a bright spot in my day. I make a point to respond to every (thoughtful) email I receive.
I’ve connected to a much broader variety of people this way than I do in daily life, and it’s amazing how much you can learn from someone if you’re open to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint</title>
      <link>https://marlisschneider.github.io/imprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marlisschneider.github.io/imprint/</guid>
      <description>Imprint   Contact   Marlis Schneider
Augartenstrasse 84
68165 Mannheim
GERMANY
Email: marlis dot schneider at nhh dot no
Disclaimer   Accountability for Content  The contents of our pages have been created with the utmost care. However, we cannot guarantee the contents&#39; accuracy, completeness or topicality. According to statutory provisions, we are furthermore responsible for our own content on these web pages. In this matter, please note that we are not obliged to monitor the transmitted or saved information of third parties, or investigate circumstances pointing to illegal activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nordic Seminar in Behavioral Economics</title>
      <link>https://marlisschneider.github.io/seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marlisschneider.github.io/seminar/</guid>
      <description>Soon to come.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast</title>
      <link>https://marlisschneider.github.io/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marlisschneider.github.io/podcast/</guid>
      <description>Soon to come.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://marlisschneider.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marlisschneider.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>You can find my CV here. Research   All my research projects are early stage work and still very much in development. I will update/provide more information in the future.
(Last updated 02/05/2022)
1. Aspirations and Intergenerational Mobility 2. Differences in Help-Seeking Behavior of Children 3. Teacher&amp;rsquo;s Beliefs About the Process of Human Capital Formation </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://marlisschneider.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marlisschneider.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>Resources   Below you find resources (e.g. books, presentations, twitter threads, blog posts etc.) that I came across and which help(ed) me along the way. Maybe they are of interest for you as well: Have a look!
This collection is work in progress and will be updated on a continued basis. Resources are listed without a particular order.
(Last updated 23/08/2022)
Finding Research Questions     Stephen Redding &amp;ndash; The Transition to PhD Research</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
